// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What does HTML stand for?",
    answer: "Hyper Text Markup Language",
    options: [
      "Hyper Text Preprocessor",
      "Hyper Text Markup Language",
      "Hyper Text Multiple Language",
      "Hyper Tool Multi Language",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What does CSS stand for?",
    answer: "Cascading Style Sheet",
    options: [
      "Common Style Sheet",
      "Colorful Style Sheet",
      "Computer Style Sheet",
      "Cascading Style Sheet",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "What does PHP stand for?",
    answer: "Hypertext Preprocessor",
    options: [
      "Hypertext Preprocessor",
      "Hypertext Programming",
      "Hypertext Preprogramming",
      "Hometext Preprocessor",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "What does SQL stand for?",
    answer: "Structured Query Language",
    options: [
      "Stylish Question Language",
      "Stylesheet Query Language",
      "Statement Question Language",
      "Structured Query Language",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What does XML stand for?",
    answer: "eXtensible Markup Language",
    options: [
      "eXtensible Markup Language",
      "eXecutable Multiple Language",
      "eXTra Multi-Program Language",
      "eXamine Multiple Language",
    ],
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "How do you target elements with HTML Tags in Javascript?",
    answer: "document.getElementsByTagName",
    options: [
      "document.getElementsByTagname",
      "document.getElementsByTagName",
      "document.querySelector",
      "document.getelmentbytag",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What does DOM in Javascript mean?",
    answer: "Document Object Model",
    options: [
      "Document Object Model",
      "Domestic Object Model",
      "Directory Object Model",
      "Dock Object Model",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "The innerHTML method is used to?",
    answer: "get or replace the content of HTML elements",
    options: [
      "get or replace the content of HTML elements",
      "delete HTML element",
      "erase information about HTML element",
      "let the user get more elements",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "document.appendChild is used to?",
    answer: "add an HTML element",
    options: [
      "add an HTML element",
      "remove an HTML element",
      "replace an HTML element",
      "create HTML element",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "document.replaceChild is used to?",
    answer: "replace an HTML element",
    options: [
      "replace an HTML element",
      "replace an HTML tag",
      "delete an HTML element permanently",
      "create a new HTML element",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "document.querySelector is used to?",
    answer: "select HTML elements",
    options: [
      "select HTML elements",
      "deselect HTML elements",
      "delete HTML elements",
      "create HTML elements",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Can the value of 'const' in Javascript be reassigned?",
    answer: "No",
    options: ["No", "Yes", "Sometimes", "Never"],
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question:
      "Which of these can be used to target same elements by HTML class?",
    answer: "document.getElementsByClassName",
    options: [
      "document.getElementbyclass",
      "document.getElementByclass",
      "document.getElementsByClassName",
      "document.className",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "document.write can be used to?",
    answer: "write directly into the HTML output stream",
    options: [
      "delete directly into the output stream",
      "edit directly into HTML ouput stream",
      "write directly into the HTML output stream",
      "create new HTML element",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which of these can be used to trigger events when you click?",
    answer: "onclick",
    options: ["clickit", "clicker", "clickit", "onclick"],
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "The toString() method does what?",
    answer: "returns a number as a string",
    options: [
      "returns a word as number",
      "returns a number as a string",
      "returns a string as an object",
      "returns an array to string",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "toPrecision() method in Javascript can be used to?",
    answer: "return a number within a specified length",
    options: [
      "return a number within a specified length",
      "return a word within a specified length",
      "return a object",
      "return an array",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "The Number() method can be used to?",
    answer: "convert javascript variables to numbers",
    options: [
      "convert javascript objects to numbers",
      "let javascript objects turn to booleans",
      "convert javascript variables to numbers",
      "change numbers to strings",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "The parseInt method can be used to?",
    answer: "parse a string and return a whole number",
    options: [
      "parse an array and return a fixed number",
      "return different strings",
      "parse a string and return a whole number",
      "make a string an object",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Can Number() be  used to convert dates to numbers?",
    answer: "Yes",
    options: ["No", "Sometimes", "Never", "Yes"],
  },
  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "How can the length of an array be known?",
    answer: "Array.length",
    options: ["Array.length", "Array.long", "Array.number", "Array.width"],
  },
  {
    numb: 22,
    question: "The difference between Arrray and Objects is that?",
    answer: "Arrays have numbered index while objects don't",
    options: [
      "Arrays have word index while objects don't",
      "Arrays have numbered index while objects don't",
      "Arrays have normal index while objects don't",
      "Arrays have string index while objects don't",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "What does the join() array method do?",
    answer: "join array elements into a string",
    options: [
      "separate array elements",
      "delete array elements",
      "distriute array elements",
      "join array elements into a string",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "What does the pop() method in javascript do?",
    answer: "remove last element from an array",
    options: [
      "remove last element from an array",
      "add new element to an array",
      "remove first element in an array",
      "delete all elements in an array",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "What does the push() method in javascript do?",
    answer: "adds new element to the array",
    options: [
      "adds old element to the array",
      "removes old element to the array",
      "adds new element to the array",
      "change element in the array",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 26,
    question: "The shift() method in an array can?",
    answer: "remove first array element and shift other elements",
    options: [
      "add new element to the end of array",
      "delete any new element at the end of array",
      "remove first array element and shift other elements",
      "add new element at the beginning of array",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 27,
    question: "Which of these array methods can be used to join two arrays",
    answer: "concat()",
    options: ["add()", "string()", "delete()", "concat()"],
  },
  {
    numb: 28,
    question: "The unshift() method can be used to?",
    answer: "adds a new element at the beginning of array",
    options: [
      "adds a new element at the end of array",
      "deletes element at the beginning of array",
      "adds a new element at the beginning of array",
      "deletes element at the end of array",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 29,
    question: "You can create a new array from an existing array using the?",
    answer: "slice()",
    options: ["splice()", "slice()", "delete()", "new()"],
  },
  {
    numb: 30,
    question: "Which of these is the correct combination to declare variables?",
    answer: "const, let, var",
    options: ["const, let, var", "let, var", "const, let", "var, const"],
  },
];
